# Joshua Shepherd

🗣 Birmingham, England, United Kingdom 🗷 josh\_shepherd@outlook.com 🛘 +447554665000 🛅 in/joshshepherd- 🕳 https://www.joshlmao.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the entertainment industry. Skilled in C#, C++, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Unity & Unreal Engine. Strong engineering professional with Games Development focused in Computer Science from University of Wolverhampton. I also have basic Mandarin skills

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Junior Software Engineer**

Simworx

September 2015 - March 2018, Kingswinford, UK

Create and maintained in house programs using C# and Windows Presentation Foundations (WPF). Used Model-View-ViewModel (MVVM) in all C# WPF programs & used bug tracking software like Trello. Helped to create a in-house show control program using UI & back end. Developed a Unity application to visualize 3/6 Degrees of Freedom (DoF) motion in VR. Helped with companies IT, assisting employees with help

#### **Content Creator**

**Youtube Content Creator** 

August 2012 - August 2015, West Midlands, United Kingdom

I created YouTube gaming content for audiences. My videos ranged from tutorials to game play videos in games such as Gwent, Grand Theft Auto V, Minecraft and more. I aimed to be entertaining while providing people with good content to watch. My channel is available to view here (https://youtube.com/JoshLmao)

#### **Crew Member**

McDonalds

December 2013 - February 2014, West Midlands, United Kingdom

I worked for a couple months as a Crew Member where I mostly communicated with customers through Drive-Thru taking orders and handling cash, while also helping to prepare food.

# **PROJECTS**

#### Genify

In my spare time while at University, I started working on a website that could detect your current Spotify song and display the relevant lyrics from Genius and also get the music video from Youtube. The project is open source on available on Github and works within a matter of seconds.

#### Lumiere - Ludum Dare 39 Entry Game

In October 2018, I wanted to challenge myself and joined the Ludum Dare content. I created a game from an idea in one weekend where I had to create all the assets & code from scratch, all open source and available to play. The idea was "Running out of power"

# DotA Clicker VR - Virtual Reality Clicker Game

An unfinished virtual reality game I spent a lot of time and effort on inside Unity. Concept was for a clicker game inside virtual reality using the DotA hero models, map and assets. Currently unreleased & closed source but with public video (https://youtu.be/mZWSmosu5DM)

#### **EDUCATION**

# **BcS Computer Science (Games Development)**

University of Wolverhampton • West Midlands, United Kingdom • 2021

#### **Multiple Diplomas in ICT**

TDM Wyre Academy · Birmingham, United Kingdom · 2016

## **Secondary School Qualifications**

Hillcrest School & Community College • Netherton, United Kingdom • 2012

## **SKILLS**

Core: C#, C++, .NET Framework, Python, Object Orientated Programming (OOP)

Tools: Unreal Engine, Unity, Git, Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF), Virtual Reality, Xamarin

Web: HTML(5), CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, NodeJS, React